Can you introduce
your
home and
오늘은 어떤 상황에서도 자신있게 나를
소개하는 [음악] 영어, 매력 어필할
수 있는 영어 표현들을 모두 알려
드리겠습니다. 자기 소개를 영어로
해보라고 할 때 항상 처음에 되게
어색한 거 같아요. 어떻게 말을
시작해야 될지. You need to
start with a
greeting. You can
say something very
simple like, "Hi
everyone. This is
probably the most
natural and it can
be used in almost
every setting. Of
course, you can also
say hello everyone
or if it's a little
bit of a more
professional
setting, you could
say good afternoon,
good morning, or
good evening." Not
ladies and
gentlemen, [웃음]
that sounds like
you're going to do a
magic show or
something. Ladies
and gentlem
>> 그럼 인사하고 나서는 무슨 말 하면
좋아요? You need to
tell everyone your
name. I think most
people in Korea
learned my name is
blank, which is
totally fine. It's
correct, but it
definitely sounds a
little bit more
textbooky and not as
natural in
conversation. So
instead you can say,
I'm blank. I'm C.
I'm home but shorter
so it's easier. It's
easier. If you're in
a group setting
where most of the
people you, you can
also say for those
of you who don't
know me, I'm blank.
For those of you who
don't know me, I'm s
professional.
>> 그 이름 말하고 나서는 어떤 것들이
오면 자연스러운 소개가 되나요? I
thinkyon to say
where from nextally
depending on the
situation. It's a
very international
group or even in the
US people might be
from different
states. So a lot of
people say where
they're from. You
can simply say I'm
from Blank. I'm from
Michigan. I'm from
the US. I'm from
Busan. Mhm. If you
moved away from your
hometown, you can
also say, "I'm
originally from
Blank, but I live in
Blank now. I'm
originally from the
US but I live in
Korea now." Another
commonly used phrase
is born and raised.
This is where you
spent most of your
childhood or maybe
all of your
childhood. I was
born and raised in
Michigan. I was born
and raised in. 이건
상대방한테 질문할 때도 되게 좋은 거
같아요. small크할 때. You
born and raised from
here?
>> Not from you born
and raised here.
[웃음]
>> 역시 you born and
raised here.
>> 여기 사람이에요. 약간 이런
느낌이죠.
>> No, I was originally
from but I live in.
>> 음.
>> 알았어. 이제 이렇게 하면 되는
거예요, 여러분.
>> Next, most people
would introduce
their job or where
they work. You can
do this very simply
by saying I'm a
blank. I'm a
marketer. I'm a
English teacher. I'm
a cameraman.
Exactly. At a
networking event or
in a professional
setting, sometimes
it's better to give
more detail and add
where you work. So
you can do this by
saying, I'm a blank
at blank. I'm a
marketer at Google.
I'm an engineer at
Samsung. 회사나 이런 걸 좀
밝히고 싶지 않을 때는 어떻게해요?
You can use the word
in I work in and
then name the
department or your
line of work. I work
in tech. I work in
English education.
학생이면 어떻게 말해야 돼요?
There is a few ways
that you could do
this. First you can
simply say I'm a
student at blank and
name your school.
I'm a student at
UCLA. Or you can say
what you're
studying. I'm
currently studying
law at university or
I'm currently
studying engineering
at university.
>> My hobby is
I know a lot of
people say my hobby
is because that
might have been what
they learned. And
again this is
correct. There is
nothing wrong with
that sentence.
However, it does
sound very bookish.
I don't think of
Americans naturally
in conversation. You
can simply say I
love blank. I love
reading.
>> 단어들을 쓰네. True. I
feel like all the
textbook ones are
harder.
>> I think this is
easier.
>> Love보다 좀 더 멋있게 말할 수
있는 건 없어요. 자기 소개하는데 뭐
있어 보여야 되잖아. A big
fan of something.
>> 오 I like this.
>> A big fan of coffee.
A big fan of
running. I'm a big
fan of fantasy
novels.
>> Are you?
>> No, you are. [웃음]
Webtunes. Webtunes.
I'm a huge fan of
Webtune. Mhm. You
can also say I'm
really into
something. This one
is especially if
it's like you're
into it. Lat. Of
course, it can be a
long thing.
좀 더 자연스럽게 나에 대해서
사람들한테 알릴 수 있는 좋은
표현들이네요.
I joined to blank
to make new friends.
I joined this group
to practice my
English. a little
more generally. You
can also say, "I'm
here because I'm
here because I just
moved here and want
to make new friends.
I'm here because I'm
moving to the US
soon, so I need to
practice my
English." You can
keep it very short
and simple. Now,
you're at the end of
yourself
introduction. A good
way to finish is to
simply say, "Nice to
meet you all. Thanks
for having me." This
is especially good
if you're a guest
somewhere.
보통 한국에서는 사람들한테 자기
소개하고 나서 잘 부탁드립니다 뭐
이렇게 얘기하거든요. 영어에서도
비슷한 표현 없나?
English, but somees
vi are looking
forward to getting
excited to be part
of the team. 그건 약간
회사 첫날 외국계 회사거나 아니면 뭐
어디 출장 가셨을 때 프로젝트에
참여했다거나 이럴 때 유용하게 쓰실
수 있겠네요.
>> and it.
>> 저희가 한국에 살다 보니까 실제로
외국인 분들을 만나서 이렇게
연습하기가 좀 어려운데 그럴 때
어떻게 좀 영어 공부를 할 수
있을까요? 캠블리.
>> 오늘 영상은 캠블리에서 제작 지원을
해 주셨습니다. 캠블리에서는
여러분들의 영어 수준, 관심사,
그리고 억양까지 선택해서 원하는
튜터분들과 맞춤형 수업을 하실 수가
있습니다. 그래서 오늘 배운 표현들을
실제로 외국인 튜터분들과 함께 연습을
하면서 내 걸로 채화를 해 보실 수가
있으세요. 저도 종종 영어 감각을
잃지 않기 위해서 사용하는데요. 제가
이런 걸 한다고 하면 아니 캘리
쌤이랑 살고 있는데 무슨 영어
공부냐라고 하실 수 있겠지만 [음악]
저희가 연애한지가 13년이 넘었기
때문에 저희가 그렇게 어 말을
디테일하게 나누지 않습니다.
>> 건강해요. [웃음]
>> 제가 써보면서 느낀 건 캠블리의
튜터분들이 굉장히 프렌리 하셔서
수업이 부담스럽지 않고 편하게 떠드는
느낌으로 수업을 진행하실 수가
있습니다. 지금 캠블리에서 연중 최대
할인 행사를 하고 있다고 합니다.
최대 50%까지 할인이 되는 캘리쌤
전용 코드를 저희가 받아왔고요. 아래
더보기란에 있는 링크에 코드를
입력하시고 활용하시면 할인이 된
가격으로 수업을 진행해 보실 수가
있습니다. 원어민 선생님들과 대화를
해 보시고 싶으셨던 분들은 한번
캠블리 수업 해 보시면 좋겠습니다.
But today prti with
me
>> 캘리쌤 먼저 한번 보여 주세요.
긴장긴장. [목을 가다듬음] Good
morning everyone.
For those of you who
don't know me, I'm
Call. I'm originally
from Michigan, but I
live in Busan now.
I'm an English
teacher and content
creator. I love
teaching natural
English through
vlogs. I'm here to
share some tips for
improving your
English speaking
skills. Thanks for
having me.
[박수]
Hey, [웃음]
you try a casual
setting. Say you're
going to like a
language exchange
meeting.
>> Hi everyone. I'm
home. I was born and
raised in. I work in
English education. I
love traveling and
I'm really into
learning new
languages. I join
this group to
practice my English
and meet new people.
Nice to meet you all
and I'm looking for
to getting to know
everyone.
>> 이게 되게 쉬운데 또 연습이 굉장히
또 필요하네.
>> 연습해.
>> 어, 연습하겠습니다.
>> 어, 연습해. 같이 영어
공부해보자고요.
>> 저희 구독자님들이 어떤 분들인지
너무너무 궁금합니다. 저희도 탑글
달아드릴게요.
>> for watching and see
next time.